<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hivedocs.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://hivedocs.info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-16T20:05:30-08:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Hive Chain Documentation</title><subtitle>Your resource for various levels of Hive Documentation.</subtitle><author><name>site curated by: @inertia</name></author><entry><title type="html">Core dev meeting #42</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/11/07/core-dev-meeting-42.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Core dev meeting #42" /><published>2022-11-07T14:42:42-08:00</published><updated>2022-11-07T14:42:42-08:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/11/07/core-dev-meeting-42</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/11/07/core-dev-meeting-42.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42">
![social_hive_light.jpg](https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/howo/23wN2RDCNPLiYdw6WJdTT7vXKrdkPN9WGeQg69m15z27Bqj1yDiYS5bo2Dwn4DGHByM2C.jpg)

Hello,

I'm really sorry about the lack of video, we had recording problems, and couldn’t record the meeting.

Instead I wrote some notes to give you an idea of what was discussed, I'm sorry this is incomplete and we'll switch to @gtg's video solution next so that those issues won't happen again.

## Developers sync: 

On my end I mostly spent time updating my hivemind pull requests following the hardfork changes and supporting RC delegation questions (many heart attacks of people telling me it doesn’t work when in fact it’s something they did wrong).

Then I started working on implementing a feature request by @brianoflondon for recurrent transfers: https://gitlab.syncad.com/hive/hive/-/issues/382 

On @blocktrades side (this is somewhat of a non-exhaustive list and will probably be in greater details in a post of his own):

There was some cleanup work following hard fork 26/27, doing some performance analysis on nodes, to see how things have changed.

Then they pushed a bunch of small changes:

- Fixed a problem with shutdowns that could happen sometimes when you did ctrl + c on a node.

- Fixes and improvements to the block statistics 

- Added more RC statistics in the form of daily report, with a new API about it (this will happen in hf 27.1)

- New api calls for updated witness scheduling

- CLI wallet side, fixed a longstanding bug to allow controlling it from websockets.

- Updated our cryptography lib to increase performance (tests ongoing but so far the initial testing shows a 40% increase !)

- New block log utility to help manage compressed block logs:

   - Comparing compressed block logs to output a checksum even though they were compressed using different methods
   - Truncating a compressed block log (previously you had to uncompress, truncate, then re-compress) 

-  Improved get_block_range by forcing it to use http to improve performance due to a websocket issue. The current suspect is that websockets is doing compression which causes slowdowns 


## Adding a VOP to record successful RC delegation

We talked a bunch about the potential use cases and  potential edge cases and issues.

The main discussion revolved around the fact that it’s hard to track if an RC delegation got executed or not (and what was executed). But after some back and forth, we concluded that since the node rejects incorrect transactions, it made sense to let the custom json denote of the change.

Hive version 1.27.1: 

We want to ship version 1.27.1 very soon:tm: (aka in a few weeks) to provide improvements to HAF and hivemind. We’ll try to slot in a change to RC delegations to include an RC minimum to prevent spam and improve dev experience.

We’ll try to include at the bug that @engrave brought up: https://gitlab.syncad.com/hive/hive/-/issues/338  

There's then a lot of discussions between @arcange and @blocktrades on his specific HAF setup that I don't think are really worth talking about.</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@howo",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/core-dev-meeting-42",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-howo-core-dev-meeting-42 img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/core/@howo/core-dev-meeting-42">Core dev meeting #42</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@howo">@howo</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>howo</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="core" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[many heart attacks of people telling me it doesn’t work when in fact it’s something they did wrong]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/howo/23wN2RDCNPLiYdw6WJdTT7vXKrdkPN9WGeQg69m15z27Bqj1yDiYS5bo2Dwn4DGHByM2C.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/howo/23wN2RDCNPLiYdw6WJdTT7vXKrdkPN9WGeQg69m15z27Bqj1yDiYS5bo2Dwn4DGHByM2C.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Help with Hive getting added to Wikipedia</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/media/wikipedia/2022/11/04/help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Help with Hive getting added to Wikipedia" /><published>2022-11-04T11:52:54-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T11:52:54-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/media/wikipedia/2022/11/04/help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/media/wikipedia/2022/11/04/help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia">![](https://i.imgur.com/n2nbSXD.jpg)

Hey Hivers!

After seeing a Tweet from [acidyo ](https://www.peakd.com/@acidyo)that showed that some brand using our logo I just went off and thought it was absolutely bonkers. On top of that, this brand is also using the exact name. Hive. I'm not going to share this Tweet here, to prevent more traffic from going to their website (as [crimsonclad ](https://www.peakd.com/@crimsonclad)mentioned), but this is just unbelievable and unacceptable.


Either way, I feel that there is still a lot to do for Hive and we must embrace Web 2, and start registering our Hive name, even if we don't use the accounts, this example shows how important it is to at least lock these names in. 

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### Wikipedia
As I was browsing Wikipedia, I noticed Hive isn't there yet.
So, here's where I just went on autopilot and started writing a page for Wikipedia. Usually, I wouldn't do this, because my morale would first want to ask someone for permission. But who do we need to ask for permission if we are writing facts? Besides, we are the chain! And once a Wikipedia page is added, it can be edited by anyone.

I also know how hard it is to get Hive on there. But, with our heads together, and some OG's that took part in starting the chain on March 20, 2020. I'm sure we can fact-check our way to Wikipedia. So, please reach out to me, as I will be busy formatting the page, or feel free to make adjustments (and keep an eye on the page) once the page is live, and accepted.

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### LET'S GET HIVE ON WIKIPEDIA
Currently working on a "declined" draft for Hive, which gives me/us about 6 months to submit a new version of it.

1. Facts
2. No biased tone of voice (the greatest, best, unique, etc.)
3. No political/sides --&gt; neutral only

<br /><br />

If I were to think for myself, I'd like to add the following. But if you have better suggestions to add. Do share. Take a look at Bitcoins Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin &lt;-- this is what we need. Dump any articles you can find about Hive here, and if you have time, do a short non-biased summary.

<br />

1.	History
a.	Founding (2020)
2.	Design
a.	Assets
b.	Accounts
c.	Nodes
d.	Transactions
3.	Applications
4.	Notes
5.	References

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
```
### History

##### Founding 2020
Hive was founded on March 17, 2020, and launched on March 20, 2020, by a vast community of decentralization proponents. Hive is a hard fork of Steem, developed by Daniel Larimer, and is under further development by the Hive community itself. The announcement of the Hive launch was made on the 17th of March 2020., by the official account of Hive, which was created on the 6th of March 2020

<br />

##### Hostile Takeover
In 2020, Justin Sun acquired Steemit Inc.[a]. Dan Larimer left Steemit Inc. before the sale, and Ned Scott sold Steemit Inc. for roughly $8 million to Justin Sun. A significant number of stakeholders got their tokens stripped away[3], which happened right after Justin Sun took over the blockchain Steem. This event led to the creation of Hive, a fork of the Steem blockchain, created by a decentralized community.

<br />

##### Hard forks
```CTA:Anyone```

HF20: Introduction of Resource Credits (RCs) [6]. RCs are non-transferable credits that accrue to each Hive account based on how much Hive Power (HP) it has. An account spends RC when it transacts on the Hive blockchain. RCs regenerate over 5 days. If an account doesn’t have sufficient credits, the transaction will not be allowed to occur.

<br /><br /><br />
### Design

<br />

##### Assets
The Hive network comes with two classes of cryptocurrency assets named HIVE and Hive Backed Dollars (HBD). Moreover, HIVE exists both in a liquid form (simply called HIVE) and a staked form (called Hive Power). HIVE is the liquid currency of the Hive ecosystem. It may be traded, staked, bought, and sold. Hive Backed Dollars are intended to be pegged to the United States Dollar (USD) at a one-to-one rate. Hive Power (HP), the staked form of HIVE, is vested during a process referred to as a ”power up”. Upon being powered up, ‘’Hive Power’’ can then be entirely or partially un-staked at will, in a process referred to as a ”power down”. Staked HIVE then returns to its liquid form (i.e. HIVE) in equal amounts over 13 weeks period, with a segment delivered every 7 days.

<br />

##### Accounts
Accounts on the Hive blockchain, are Self-Sovereign-Digital-Identities (SSDI) to provide flexible functionality based on a set of standards-based primitives for building decentralized identity applications in a modular manner. Accounts are also universal and allow instant access to any application that is being built on top of the Hive blockchain.

<br />

##### Addresses
All Hive accounts are non-fungible tokens that serve as easy to recognize user-handles, and wallet addresses. 

<br />

##### Nodes

**Witness nodes**
```CTA:Anyone```
**Seed nodes**
```CTA:Anyone```
**API nodes**
```CTA:Anyone```
<br />

##### Transactions
```CTA:Anyone```

<br /><br /><br />
### Applications
```CTA:Anyone```

```
<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />


![image.png](https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/rubencress/23tHLr3nGwBoDWs5fdHA7gGAJcNn8g99ZmqkdmRVh95Tz7DhF85noFomEMBxMcwVvq2Xd.png)

**Blockchain versus Cryptocurrency**
There is a difference between blockchain and cryptocurrency. Due to the records of Wikipedia and comments here that validate that, the chances that just HIVE (or HBD for that matter) is getting listed, will be very slim (which is to be expected). On the other hand, if we talk about _just_ the blockchain, and have less focus on the cryptocurrency (HIVE and HBD) and refer to or just mention built-on-top applications, I think the chances are much higher to get Hive on Wikipedia.

**Once you understand that Hive is more than HIVE, Hivepower or HBD**
The common mistake many people make is confusing Hive with currency or a social blogging platform. Social Media Platforms have become a big part of our lives, which makes it understandable that Hive is huge as well. What if I told you that a Social Media Platform like Hive.blog (or any other interface), is just only one possibility that we can create on Hive, what would you say? What is Hive?

Hive is more or less a, distributed computing project, simplified. A decentralized network that runs validated data, the output of this data is what we’re reading right now, made possible by applications build on top of Hive. Hive is decentralized, but for example, LeoFinance itself is centralized, which is in this case not a bad thing at all. You see, LeoFinance utilizes the Hive blockchain, which shares only validated, and decentralized output data. For example, your LeoFinance blog is readable on Hive.blog, PeakD, Ecency, etcetera. This is a huge difference if we were to talk about HIVE the currency, which is a currency, simplified. 


![image.png](https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/rubencress/23t7xG4YgVQ3M7kaQNSwTxq4SVBsHysZt4mNsjcS9Xnv5ECtSH9PZMH8fDp1B8q4PE7MJ.png)


From this perspective, we basically strip down Hive to the core, and are left with just the things that make Hive, Hive. And here is where we see the magic. And if we can explain this magic, with "backed" 3rd party non-biased, and non-crypto-web-related articles, we should be able to get Hive listed. Oh the irony of Web2...


<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### Formatting
The formatting looks familiar to MarkDown. 

![](https://i.imgur.com/gHyzKOx.png)
<br />
### Visual

![](https://i.imgur.com/HaEGfRo.png)
<br />
### Declined
This is way too little information to get accepted on Wikipedia, I wasn't expecting to be reviewed this fast, but it's nice to receive some feedback this fast so I know what to look out for. 

![](https://i.imgur.com/qs3H8Jm.png)

I've started to write a bit more and thought it would be nice to start from the beginning.
If someone knows exactly which block number Hive was loose from Steem, that would be amazing. Couldn't find anything in block #41801981 https://hiveblocks.com/b/41801981, but it's good to see my friend louis88 there. 

Any information you provide is more than welcome! If you're a (dApp) developer, and you want your full name on here, please let me know as well. 

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### The Infobox
The infobox visually looks like this. Below you will find the format where I can add information. I'd like to add our core-dev team to it under "developers". The current list of Witness nodes is limited to 100 on Hiveblocks.com, out of 100, 13 are inactive, but I have a feeling we have more than 100 (Witness) Nodes running.

![](https://i.imgur.com/0atjCpw.png)

```
{{Infobox distributed computing project
| name                   = Hive
| logo                   = File:Horizontal.svg|thumb|Hive logo
| logo_caption           = Logo for Hive
| author                 = 
| developer              = Martin Lees, Dan Notestein, Gandalf, Abit, Bartek Wrona, ABW
| released               = {{Start date and age|2020|03|20|df=yes}}
| discontinued           = <!-- Set to yes if software is discontinued, otherwise omit. -->
| latest release version = ‘Evolution’
| latest release date    = {{Start date and age|2022|10|24|df=yes}}
| frequently updated     = Yes
| latest preview version = 
| latest preview date    = 
| status                 = Active
| goal                   = 
| software               = 
| funding                = No VC funding
| programming language   = [[C++|C++]], [[Python (programming language)|Python]]
| operating system       = [[Cross-platform software|Cross-platform]]
| platform               = 
| size                   = 
| language               = Multilingual, but primarily English
| genre                  = [[Distributed computing]]
| license                = [[Open-source license]]s
| standard               = 
| as of                  = 
| performance            = 
| active users           = 
| total users            = 
| active hosts           = 87/100 (2022-09-10)<ref>{{Cite web |title=Witnesses – hiveblocks.com - The Hive Network &amp; Node Explorer |url=https://hiveblocks.com/witnesses |access-date=2022-11-04 |website=hiveblocks.com}}</ref>
| total hosts            = 
| website                = {{URL|hive.io}}
}}


{{Infobox cryptocurrency
| currency_name           = HIVE
| image_1                 = File:Icon of Hive.svg
| image_2                 = File:Icon of Hive.svg
| alt1                    = Icon for HIVE
| alt2                    = Icon for HIVE-Backed Dollar
| image_title_1           = HIVE
| image_title_2           = HBD
| symbol                  = 
| alt_symbol_title_1      = 
| alt_symbol_1            = 
| code                    = 
| previous_names          = 
| nickname                = 
| precision               = 
| white_paper             = https://hive.io/whitepaper.pdf
| implementations         = 
| code_repository         = https://gitlab.syncad.com/hive
| project_fork_of         = Steem
| developer               = 
| source_model            = 
| block_explorer          = https://hiveblocks.com
| ledger_start            = {{Start date and age|2016|03|24|df=yes}}
| split_height            = 
| split_date              = 
| split_from              = 
| split_ratio             = 
| hash_function           = 
| issuance_schedule       = 
| timestamping            = 
| merged_mining_parent    = 
| block_time              = 3000 milliseconds
| block_reward            = 
| circulating_supply      = 
| supply_limit            = 
| exchange_rate           = 
| market_cap              = 
| using_countries         = 
| footnotes               = 
| catISO4217              = 
}}
```

**If you know, you know... I don't. If you do: Please fill in the blanks &lt;3**

### REF links
Ref links are a BIG thing on Wikipedia, without adding reliable sources -other- than just Hive's mentions etc. it will be a really difficult task to get Hive on Wikipedia.

The formatting for reference URLs is as follows:
```
<ref>{{Cite web |last=AUTHOR_NAME |date=PUBLISHED_DATE |title=ARTICLE_TITLE |url=LIVE_URL_TO_WEB |access-date=ACCESSED_ON_TODAYS_DATE |website=PARENT_DOMAIN_NAME}}</ref>
```

Finding articles about Hive is already a PAIN due to Google's "shadow ban". &lt;-- this is giving even more reason to have a Wikipedia that is capable of storing -all- this these valuable information in articles. Wikipedia is based on facts, not on controllable algorithms like Google. 

If you'd like to help, make sure to check out that the article is an in-depth article with date and author included.

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### This comment section
Please, I encourage you to provide factual non-biased information about the Hive blockchain, and if possible, provide an outside source (URL), so I can implement your bit in the wiki page. Use the comment section for this. Also, please check if someone has submitted what you're about to submit (or has already been added by me). My vote isn't worth much, but I'll try to see if I can curate any work you've shared with me. 

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### Hive LOGO

I've added the Hive logo ([roelandp](https://www.peakd.com/@roelandp), it's CC licensed right?) ```https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Icon_of_Hive.svg```, please let me know if this reference is fine or needs to be adjusted. I've also added the HIVE and HBD logo to give more body to the info-boxes. Will need to re-upload for proper licensing.

According to RoelandP's [blogpost](https://peakd.com/hive/@roelandp/hello-hive-first-post-hive-becoming-of-the-brand), I believe it is a CC BY-ND-4.0 license (could you please verify this, Roeland?)

<br /><br /><hr /><br /><br />
### Wiki guru?
Hit me up on Discord! Let's make this page real and help me out. All the help is welcome.



If you're curious about the draft: [https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Draft:Hive_(blockchain)](https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Draft:Hive_(blockchain)). ALL HELP IS WELCOME!

Cheers,
Ruben

ps; I'll be updating this page as I update the Wikipedia page.
pps; I'll be removing tags for updates, dont want to spam.</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@rubencress",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-rubencress-help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive/@rubencress/help-with-hive-getting-added-to-wikipedia">Help with Hive getting added to Wikipedia</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@rubencress">@rubencress</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>rubencress</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="media" /><category term="wikipedia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After seeing a Tweet from acidyo that showed that some brand using our logo I just went off and thought it was absolutely bonkers.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.imgur.com/n2nbSXD.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.imgur.com/n2nbSXD.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hive x Ledger: Support for Ledger Hardware Wallets</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hive x Ledger: Support for Ledger Hardware Wallets" /><published>2022-11-01T10:54:51-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T10:54:51-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets">![image.png](https://images.hive.blog/DQmY6V5CTeBWrQ6D72dG7K4pgP8bvHpHXz3V6xVsANDi5pc/image.png)

We are thrilled to announce that Hive has been integrated with and is now available on Ledger Nano S, Nano S Plus, and Nano X hardware wallets effective today, November 1, 2022.

The integration is the work of @engrave: 
&gt; Ledger wallets are secure, trusted, and widely available. That makes them the perfect partner for the Hive decentralized blockchain. Ledger hardware wallets allow Hive to utilize an unlimited set of private and public key pairs to secure multiple Hive accounts with the same device. Read more [here](https://peakd.com/hive/@engrave/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger). 

Much technical effort went into this integration. Hive does not use the unspent transaction output (UTXO) protocol model. The Ledger implementation for Hive utilizes the [SLIP-0048: Deterministic Key Hierarchy for Graphene-based Networks](https://github.com/satoshilabs/slips/blob/master/slip-0048.md) standard  which extends BIP-44 standard to match role-based model.

The Hive-Ledger implementation allows users to view and manage public keys using a special [Hive Ledger Wallet](https://hiveledger.io) companion application. It facilitates the review of transaction properties such as transfers and staking amounts, HIVE and HBD recipients, key derivation paths, delegation, governance voting, and much more. All operations and their properties are visible on a device screen. Users must approve transactions with a digital signature issued by the device.  

This is an amazing development and addition to the Hive ecosystem! 

- [How to use Hive Ledger Wallet](https://peakd.com/engrave/@engrave/how-to-use-hive-ledger-wallet)
- [How to create cold storage wallet with Ledger Nano and earn 20% HBD stable coin interest](https://peakd.com/engrave/@engrave/how-to-create-cold-storage-wallet-with-ledger-nano-and-earn-20-hbd-stable-coin-interest)

**About Ledger:**
Founded in 2014, [Ledger](https://www.ledger.com) is a global digital asset and Web3 platform. More than 20 percent of the world’s crypto assets are secured through Ledger Nano wallets. Headquartered in Paris and Vierzon, France, with offices in London, New York, Singapore, and Portland, Ledger has a team of more than 700 professionals developing a variety of products and services to enable individuals and companies to securely buy, store, swap, and manage crypto assets. Devices include Ledger hardware wallets with more than 5 million units sold in more than 180 countries.

Ledger combines a hardware wallet—Nano S Plus or Nano X—and the Ledger Live app to offer consumers an easy start in their crypto journey while maintaining full control over their digital assets. 

With its ease of use, Ledger allows a user to begin investing in digital assets while achieving financial freedom in a safe and stress-free environment The Ledger Academy is a content portal that provides customers with education on the emerging Web3 ecosystem. Ledger has also developed Ledger Enterprise, a digital asset custody and security solution for institutional investors and financial players.</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@hiveio",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://hive.blog/hive/@hiveio/hive-x-ledger-support-for-ledger-hardware-wallets">Hive x Ledger: Support for Ledger Hardware Wallets</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@hiveio">@hiveio</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>hiveio</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="core" /><category term="wallet" /><category term="ledger" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce that Hive has been integrated with and is now available on Ledger Nano S, Nano S Plus, and Nano X hardware wallets effective today, November 1, 2022.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.hive.blog/DQmY6V5CTeBWrQ6D72dG7K4pgP8bvHpHXz3V6xVsANDi5pc/image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.hive.blog/DQmY6V5CTeBWrQ6D72dG7K4pgP8bvHpHXz3V6xVsANDi5pc/image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hive is now officially supported by Ledger</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hive is now officially supported by Ledger" /><published>2022-11-01T10:23:57-07:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T10:23:57-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/wallet/ledger/2022/11/01/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger">![](https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/engrave/48YdnNGyye4zodge7bXCLy6bsded3n6732hGtyK3eBF4SK75e2Qet7pDJJDnuF8VyA.png)

I'm proud to announce that Ledger has finished their official review and published Hive application in their directory. **This means that Hive is now officially supported and available on all Ledger devices!** It has been already listed on [supported crypto assets](https://www.ledger.com/supported-crypto-assets) list on their official website. This is a huge milestone for Hive ecosystem as it drastically increases security and opens the ecosystem to more investors.

After almost two years of effort, countless hours of development, testing, and writing documentation, everyone can easily install Hive app directly from Ledger Live and use it to protect their accounts. In case of any problems, they can also find some official [support articles](https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/6672434290205-Hive-HIVE-?docs=true).

# Why is it important?

It is yet another milestone that Hive ecosystem has reached. Few weeks ago our core developers introduced [One-Block Irreversibility](https://peakd.com/hive-139531/@blocktrades/one-block-irreversibility-for-delegated-proof-of-stake-dpos) (changes introduced in HF26) and it puts Hive in a position of the industry leader in DPOS blockchains space. Let's take advantage of this!

## Improved security

Hardware wallets are considered one of the best ways to manage your crypto assets. Using a hardware wallet increases overall security because you never expose your private keys to the outside world. Private keys are securely stored inside the hardware and never leave it. Even if you connect the device via USB, there is no way to leak your private keys. That's essential for your account security as we all know that leaks happen all the time, even to those who take special care to prevent them.

## More exposure for Hive ecosystem

It also opens Hive to a broader audience. From now on, it can be targeted to people that rely on hardware wallets to protect their assets. It often happens, that crypto projects without hardware wallets support are not taken seriously. It is not a case anymore for Hive and combining it with 20% APR for keeping our stable coin, it makes a great opportunity to start onboarding more and more serious investors.


# Hive Ledger Wallet

 * https://hiveledger.io

[Hive Ledger Wallet](https://hiveledger.io) became the official wallet for Hive and Ledger integration. It is a featureful application that follows integration standards and allows Hive users to secure their accounts. It is available in Chrome, Opera and Brave browsers (unfortunately, other browsers do not support webUSB protocol).

![](https://i.imgur.com/oGzyWc0.png)


***

**Btw, if you don't have a Ledger wallet yet, [buy one with this affiliate link](https://shop.ledger.com/?r=d5ee0e9dc3d0) to support me!**

***

I'm also eager to implement or help implement Hive Ledger support in other wallets, like **Vessel** and **Keychain** to make the experience even better and easier for the end user.

***


If you missed my previous posts, here's the list of useful links:
 * [How to use Hive Ledger Wallet](https://peakd.com/engrave/@engrave/how-to-use-hive-ledger-wallet)
 * [How to create cold storage wallet with Ledger Nano and earn 20% HBD stable coin interest](https://peakd.com/engrave/@engrave/how-to-create-cold-storage-wallet-with-ledger-nano-and-earn-20-hbd-stable-coin-interest)

***

# FAQ

### What is it, for who and what does it do?

This is a way to secure your account. Ultimately. You can replace your authority keys with those from your hardware wallet and use it to sign any transaction. It's not going to make your Hive experience easier but it will be a great way to create a safe cold wallet. 

It is for everyone who wants to protect himself from being scammed or compromised. Keeping your `owner key` on Ledger device makes your account almost impossible to hack (this of course depends on how you treat your seed phrase). But from the key perspective - no one will have a chance to see it.


### What happens if my device breaks / I lose it?

All keys available on the device are derived from a single seed phrase in a deterministic and secure way by following SLIP-0048 standard. This means that in case of any problems with your device, you can recreate another one using the same seed phrase and replace it. You can even use multiple devices with the same seed phrase at the same time and it will work seamlessly.

### Can I use my device to protect multiple accounts?

Yes, keys can be derived from a hierarchical tree with an almost unlimited amount of branches, which means you can secure all of your accounts. I already did that and replaced owner keys in all my Hive accounts. You don't even need to remember anything - [hiveledger.io](https://hiveledger.io) will automatically discover all your accounts every time you visit it.

### Can I power up Hive that is held on Ledger?

First - it's crucial to understand that all your assets are stored in a decentralized database (blockchain) and Ledger device only keeps your private keys. This means that you can perform any operation while having an account associated with Ledger device.

You can use Ledger to sign any transaction. It includes staking (powering up), governance operations, transfers and all L2 operations as well.

### Would I still be able to vote and earn curation rewards?

As stated above - yes, you can perform any operation on Hive blockchain. It **might be difficult** at the moment because if you replace `active` and `posting` keys, you rely on hiveledger.io which does not allow you to perform social operations easily but it will be accessible when we add Ledger support to Hive Keychain.

### Can I replace only the master key to keep all social abilities like posting?

That's correct and I would say it's recommended way. If you replace your `owner` key you are sure no one can steal your account. If you keep your old `active` and `posting` keys, you can keep using Hive Keychain or whatever wallet you're using right now.

On this screen you need to unselect active and posting keys to keep the access in Hive Keychain:

![](https://i.imgur.com/I0p20gD.png)

You may want to replace all your keys only if you want to create a safe cold storage wallet that is ultimately protected.


### I was using Hive app in developer mode, should I update it?

It is recommended to disable developer mode in Ledger Live and update Hive app to the latest version. It introduces a blind signing feature that might be required to sign some of the transactions.

### I use Hive so actively that it's probably a hassle for me to sign anything with the Ledger device.

You can always replace only your owner key to ultimately protect your account, leaving current active and posting keys to be able to interact with other frontends. That's what I did. I'm able to write on peakd.com and sign it with Keychain and also interact with Hive Ledger Wallet at the same time.

***

# Call to action - Hive needs you!

This is a great opportunity for the entire ecosystem and let's take advantage of this! Please spread and share this article to reach people that might be interested in Hive. Write your own and share it on Twitter, Facebook and other social media websites! The more people will hear about Hive the better for all of us!

***

**Don't forget to support me with your witness vote! Click [here](https://vote.hive.uno/@engrave) or on the image below:**

<center>
[![](https://images.hive.blog/DQmUghvic5TCPPvVkB4iB7eXmgQ3RQ4L8jkVizvuCBW8RMT/banner_engrave%20100.png)](https://vote.hive.uno/@engrave)
</center>

</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@engrave",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-engrave-hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive/@engrave/hive-is-now-officially-supported-by-ledger">Hive is now officially supported by Ledger</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@engrave">@engrave</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>engrave</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="core" /><category term="wallet" /><category term="ledger" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm proud to announce that Ledger has finished their official review and published Hive application in their directory.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/engrave/48YdnNGyye4zodge7bXCLy6bsded3n6732hGtyK3eBF4SK75e2Qet7pDJJDnuF8VyA.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/engrave/48YdnNGyye4zodge7bXCLy6bsded3n6732hGtyK3eBF4SK75e2Qet7pDJJDnuF8VyA.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hive Authentication Services Development and Maintenance</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/tools/authentication/2022/10/23/hiveauth-proposal-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hive Authentication Services Development and Maintenance" /><published>2022-10-23T08:16:24-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-23T08:16:24-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/tools/authentication/2022/10/23/hiveauth-proposal-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/tools/authentication/2022/10/23/hiveauth-proposal-2.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2">![](https://i.imgur.com/QnlB5h6.png)

The Hive Authentication Services have been officially launched several months ago and I would like to thank everyone who has given their support and enabled its development.

### What are Hive Authentication Services?

![](https://i.imgur.com/dLPYaIT.png)

Hive Authentication Services (HiveAuth) makes it easy and secure for users to authenticate without providing any password or private key
• on any device (mobile, tablet, desktop, …)
• on any operating System (Android, iOS, Windows, macOS, Linux, …)
• on any applications (either web, desktop or mobile)

As of today, HiveAuth provides the most simple and secure 3FA authentication process.

HiveAuth solves password problems and is phishing-proof because you no longer need to provide your password or private key to any HiveAuth-enabled app or website.

![](https://i.imgur.com/ZZhk0cv.png)

More than 10K users have used it at least once to authenticate with their favorite application and the HiveAuth infrastructure handles more than 9K requests per day (authentications or transactions). And it's growing every day!

### Work done

A lot has happened since the first announcement and if you have regularly followed updates regarding HiveAuth, you know that we have never stopped working on the project, both visibly by implementing new features and behind the scenes providing help for app developers.

Here is a quick recap of the work that has been done:

* [The very first Annoucement](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-proposal)
* Creation of a guide for developers [[1]](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-developer-guide-part-1) [[2]](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-developer-guide-part-2)
* Creation of a Private Key Storage Application (PKSA) [guide](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-pksa)
* Development and open-sourcing of a [PKSA](https://github.com/hiveauth/hive-auth-pksa) example
* Creation of HiveAuth integration code [example](/@arcange/hiveauth-html-example)
* Creation of the official [HiveAuth website](https://hiveauth.com)
* Production infrastructure setup and official [Go Live](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-going-live-on-22022022)

Several important improvements have been made along the way:
* [Session Recovery Feature](/@arcange/hive-authentication-services-broken-session-recovery-feature-added)
* [New Visual Identity](/@arcange/has-visual-identity)


Developer support work has also been substantial
* creation of an open-source [HiveAuth library](/@arcange/has-wrapper-library) for developers
* Support to @mintrawa for its [Hive Authentication Client](/@mintrawa/hive-authentication-client-hac) library (HAC)
* Support to @quochuy for its [HiveAuth Client](/@quochuy/hiveauth-client-library) library
* Help for integration into [Keychain Mobile](/@keychain/hive-keychain-dhf-3-weeks-30-31)
* Help for integration into [Condenser](/@quochuy/working-on-hive-authentication-services-integration-for-the-condenser) (hive.blog)
* Help for integration into [dBuzz](/@dbuzz/dbuzz-will-be-implementing-the-hive-authentication-services-has) [[2]](/@jacuzzi/hivekey-chain-hive-authentication-services-and-you)
* Help for integration into [PeakD](/@peakd/calling-all-hiveauth-users-peakd-needs-your-input)
* Help for integration into dlux.io
* Help for integration into CryptoShots
* Integration into [Engage](/@arcange/engage-update-hiveauth)

Lot of time has also been spent on creating and maintaining a clear and exhaustive [documentation](https://docs.hiveauth.com) available at https://docs.hiveauth.com. It contains:
* presentation of the project
* detailed description of the HAS protocol
* complete guide for application developers
* complete guide for wallet developers (PKSA)
* tutorials with multiple code examples
* link to open-source repositories for PKSA and apps libraries
* visual material for developers and writers

Preparation of HiveAuth presentation for several events

* Presentation at [HiveFest 6](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=otrv7CrrYkE&amp;t=7605s)
* The [CryptoManiacs Podcast](https://3speak.tv/watch?v=jongolson/hmpalavq) with @jongolson and @taskmaster4450
* Presentation at [HiveFest 7](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dG65h-YCK8Q)
* Presentation at [Oklahoma State University](/@arcange/presenting-hiveauth-at-oklahoma-state-university) Blockchain Summit


## Request for funding

This funding proposal aims to further develop, support and raise awareness of HiveAuth as well as cover the costs of the underlying infrastructure.

### What's the benefit for Hive?

Hive Authentication Services has become the first fully decentralized authentication service backed by a blockchain. It enables the concept of ***"Your Hive account is your key"*** to become a reality, both for the Hive ecosystem and for the "outside world".

HiveAuth opens the door to countless possibilities. It also highlights the many functionality and ease of development on Hive. 

Recent presentations to audiences outside of the Hive ecosystem have clearly demonstrated that this is not only attracting audience interest in HiveAuth but also in the Hive blockchain itself.

### Budget

For this new proposal, we are applying for a daily budget of 325 HBD for a period of 12 months.

### What's the funding for?

There is still a lot of work to be done, in terms of development, support and communication. 

**1. Development roadmap**

* support for multi-sig transactions (WIP)
* support for variable timeouts for requests
* support for signing transactions with multiple operations
* support for signing transactions with multiple accounts
* support for integration into existing new Apps and PKSA
* support for multiple HAS nodes to allow load balancing and failover (WIP)
* improve the redundancy and the scalability of the infrastructure (WIP)
* dockerization of the HAS nodes for easy deployment
* creation of a HAS node deployment tutorial
* creation of new tutorials and code examples for additional development languages

and much more...

**2. Regular work**
* Code maintenance and deployment
* Support to users and (d)Apps developers
* Documentation maintenance, both for users and developers
* Communication and external awareness 

**3. Infrastructure**

* Server(s) + Firewall
* Security management and monitoring tools
* Performances monitoring tools
* Domain registration
* Backup services

## Support

I have always been easy to reach, responsive and as helpful as possible. 

If you have any questions, support is provided on [Discord](https://discord.gg/Tk5dkAgQPh)

---
# Support This Proposal:

* [Vote for this proposal (#240) on Peakd](https://peakd.com/me/proposals/240)
* [Vote for this proposal (#240) on Ecency](https://ecency.com/proposals/240)
* [Vote for this Proposal (#240) on Hive.blog](https://wallet.hive.blog/proposals)
* [Vote for this Proposal (#240) using HiveSigner](https://hivesigner.com/sign/update_proposal_votes?proposal_ids=%5B%22240%22%5D&amp;approve=true)

Thank you for your support!</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@arcange",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hiveauth-proposal-2",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-arcange-hiveauth-proposal-2 img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive-139531/@arcange/hiveauth-proposal-2">Hive Authentication Services Development and Maintenance</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@arcange">@arcange</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>arcange</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="authentication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Hive Authentication Services have been officially launched several months ago and I would like to thank everyone who has given their support and enabled its development.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.imgur.com/QnlB5h6.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.imgur.com/QnlB5h6.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">HF27 is Coming on October 24th - Some Slight Additional Evolution Needed</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/10/22/hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HF27 is Coming on October 24th - Some Slight Additional Evolution Needed" /><published>2022-10-22T10:59:21-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-22T10:59:21-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/10/22/hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/core/development/2022/10/22/hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed">
![](https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/hiveio/23t6zNLwhGYp6GuwE7AK8JC2gHRXBUbo18bBr3MxG4sfmTPUKLZPDtD8eBF1CcbucjsTD.gif)


## Hardfork 26 has been live for more than a week, and the performance improvements and new features have been incredible across the board. It may seem a bit of a shock that we need to have another quick code upgrade two weeks later! Read on for details of why HF27 is already scheduled for an important fix.

If you missed the fact that the Hive codebase has just undergone *Evolution* for expansion of ease of onboarding, higher performance, lowered costs, and other great benefits, you can find [the official explainer post here](https://hive.blog/hive/@hiveio/the-evolution-of-hive-hardfork-26). After more than a week, the new Resource Credit delegation system and features like OBI (one block irreversibility), compression, and snapshots are drastically improving quality of life for projects and users in the ecosystem. 

However, shortly after the new hardfork went live, witnesses discovered one aspect of the new codebase is not behaving exactly as it should: the block production schedule is randomly shuffling through backup witnesses improperly. Some backups are scheduled to produce a block each round (similar to a top 20 witness) for multiple rounds, while others are being skipped for much longer than they should be according to their rank. While this bug requires a quick hardfork to fix, it does not pose a threat to the blockchain, tokens and assets, and does not require a replay of infrastructure.

While there is no avenue for this shuffling issue to make it easier to attack the chain, it did impact reward incentives to backup witnesses, which could lead to a potential loss of backup witnesses in the long term. There's no doubt this has been a very frustrating time for backup witnesses who are waiting to have the shuffle land on them! It is important to note that all block production rewards were paid out at the correct rate and still at random to backup witnesses as scheduled: no additional rewards were paid, and none were missed. However, some backup witnesses have been lucky and have signed many more blocks than they normally would have, and some backup witnesses have not been scheduled at all when they normally would have been. It is very important to get this fixed as quickly as possible so that witness rank is properly impacting scheduling again, but not so fast that we disrupt exchanges, infrastructure providers, and users. 

This fix has been in testing for a week now, and is ready to be deployed. If you check Hive's witness ranking lists, you will see some witnesses have already begun signalling Version 1.27.0. While there is very little by way of code that needed to be written to correct this shuffling issue, making sure the fix does not extend node downtime is paramount, as we are still having some infrastructure catching up after HF26. 

### ♦️ What this means for witnesses:

## *You must upgrade to version 1.27.0*

**Hardfork 27 will not require a replay.** You will be able to stop your node, upgrade, and restart. There will be almost no downtime required to apply the new version that includes the scheduling fix.

**Find the 1.27.0 release tagged on the official repo here:
https://gitlab.syncad.com/hive/hive/-/tags/v1.27.0**

HF27 will come into effect on or after Monday, October 24th at 12:00 UTC, when consensus is reached.


### ♦️ What this means for our exchanges and other types of infrastructure provider:
Hardfork 27 will not require any additional downtime. Much like witness nodes, exchange and other types of nodes will be able to stop, apply the new version, and restart. Our liaisons are working with exchanges and they have nearly completed their HF26 upgrades. Applying HF27 will not require an additional period of weeks of their nodes being kept offline.

### ♦️ What this means for end users:
You will not see any additional downtime, or much of anything at all! This hardfork does absolutely nothing above and beyond fixing the scheduling issue, as well as some small changes to snapshots, which are ways of recording the state of a node at a specific period in time for faster maintenance. There are no changes to any aspects of the core blockchain code apart from these "back end" fixes. 


## While we've had a spectacular run with smooth code deployment over the past few years, it is inevitable that there will be some bumps along the way.
Every hardfork is an opportunity to improve our testing regimen and to get more and more people contributing to code and bug hunting. This particular scheduling problem is overall harmless and does indeed still distribute block production rewards randomly, but definitely has a big impact on our backup witnesses and their block production rewards. It's fair to be concerned about chain security and to operate with that in mind, but equally important to make sure that Hive's decentralized distribution continues to all of the amazing block producers securing the chain from around the world.

Working as a team and a community in co-operation, competition, and collaboration simultaneously can be really difficult. How we handle getting better with each hardfork, bug, success and hurdle is part of what has made this blockchain and its users so resilient.
## Hive's Evolution thus far has been a pretty incredible feat to bee a part of, so thank you for your contribution! 🐝
</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@hiveio",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-hiveio-hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive/@hiveio/hf27-is-coming-on-october-24th-some-slight-additional-evolution-needed">HF27 is Coming on October 24th - Some Slight Additional Evolution Needed</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@hiveio">@hiveio</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>hiveio</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="core" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Schedule Fix HF27 will come into effect on or after Monday, October 24th at 12:00 UTC, when consensus is reached.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/hiveio/23t6zNLwhGYp6GuwE7AK8JC2gHRXBUbo18bBr3MxG4sfmTPUKLZPDtD8eBF1CcbucjsTD.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://files.peakd.com/file/peakd-hive/hiveio/23t6zNLwhGYp6GuwE7AK8JC2gHRXBUbo18bBr3MxG4sfmTPUKLZPDtD8eBF1CcbucjsTD.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hive HF27 has been released for HIAB - please update (Hive-in-a-box update info)</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/tools/docker/2022/10/20/hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hive HF27 has been released for HIAB - please update (Hive-in-a-box update info)" /><published>2022-10-20T10:34:30-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-20T10:34:30-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/tools/docker/2022/10/20/hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/tools/docker/2022/10/20/hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info">As I’m currently travelling, I’ll keep this short. Apologies for any weird grammar, I’m writing this post on a tablet.

Hard fork 27 has been released for Hive witness, seed, and rpc nodes - which fixes a bug in the witness scheduler, so that backup witnesses are scheduled normally as they were in HF25.

I believe the HF triggers on Monday 24 Oct, but I’m not sure what time.

Since I’m not at home, my backup admin has built and published the HF27 docker build for HIAB servers, so you can easily upgrade your servers.

No replay is required, as it’s a minor update (treated as a HF due to consensus changes) - so you can simply install and restart:

```
./run.sh install
./run.sh restart
```

If you have a @privex Hive Node-in-a-box server - as no replay is required, you can simply install and restart as shown above, but if you have problems, we’ll be updating our templates soon, so it’ll be possible to do a standard reinstall to upgrade to HF27.

Thanks for reading!

If you like what I do, please [vote for me as a witness](https://peskd.com/witnesses)! :)</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@someguy123",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-someguy123-hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/witness-update/@someguy123/hive-hf27-has-been-released-for-hiab-please-update-hive-in-a-box-update-info">Hive HF27 has been released for HIAB - please update (Hive-in-a-box update info)</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@someguy123">@someguy123</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>someguy123</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="docker" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[New HF fixes witness scheduling - instructions on updating Hive-in-a-box + Privex NIAB]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://hivedocs.info/assets/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://hivedocs.info/assets/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">HiveSQL Update - RC Delegations data available</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/18/hivesql-update-20221018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HiveSQL Update - RC Delegations data available" /><published>2022-10-18T05:23:06-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T05:23:06-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/18/hivesql-update-20221018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/18/hivesql-update-20221018.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018">![](https://i.imgur.com/tYFgjui.png)

Retrieving information about RC delegations can be a bit tricky. Although the Hive API generally allows you to retrieve information from the blockchain, there is no API call to easily find who has delegated RCs to whom.

### HiveSQL to the rescue

Fortunately, HiveSQL allows you to retrieve related information from the `TxCustoms` table which includes all creation, modification or removal of RC delegation operations carried out by users.

However, the main difficulty comes from the fact that you have to filter custom_json operations, parse the JSON payload and perform computations with each operation to get the state of the delegation between accounts.

Add to this that you have to take into account a [bug that I discovered and reported](https://gitlab.syncad.com/hive/hive/-/issues/395) yesterday. This bug in the processing of RC delegation operations will probably be corrected soon, but it must be taken into account for existing operations.

### HiveSQL to the rescue (bis repetita)

Due to all the technical reasons mentioned above, retrieving an accurate list of delegators or delegatees is complex and resources consuming task.

That's why I added a new non-consensus state table named `RCDelegations` to the HiveSQL database in order to allow its users to retrieve RC delegations data quickly and easily.

It contains the list of all **active** RC delegations with the following info:

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|delegator|The account delegating Hive Power|
|delegatee|The account receiving Hive Power delegation|
|rc|The amount of RCs delegated|

## Documentation

HiveSQL documentation has been updated and can be viewed at https://docs.hivesql.io

## Support

If you have any questions or remarks, support for HiveSQL is provided on [Discord](https://discord.gg/kyEFDfT).

---
<center>

### Check out my apps and services
<a href="/hive/@hive.engage/stay-connected-with-your-hive-audience-and-catch-attention"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/GiNJqlm.png" /></a><a href="/@hivebuzz"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/B4UTun2.png" /></a><a href="https://hivesql.io"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/EPN8RW6.png" /></a><a href="/hive/@arcange/introducing-hive-account-recovery"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/6TWeW7V.png" /></a><a href="/@hive.autoclaim"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ih2pEOw.png" /></a></center>
<center>

### [Vote for me as a witness ![](https://i.imgur.com/2bi4SnT.png)](https://vote.hive.uno/@arcange)</center></div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@arcange",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hivesql-update-20221018",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-20221018 img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive-139531/@arcange/hivesql-update-20221018">HiveSQL Update - RC Delegations data available</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@arcange">@arcange</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>arcange</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="sql" /><category term="database" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[HiveSQL has been updated with a new table that helps find information about RC delegations faster and easier.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.imgur.com/tYFgjui.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.imgur.com/tYFgjui.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">RC Delegation Tool Update + RC -&amp;gt; HP calculation</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/tools/rc/delegation/2022/10/16/rc-delegation-tool-update-rc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RC Delegation Tool Update + RC -&amp;gt; HP calculation" /><published>2022-10-16T01:32:48-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-16T01:32:48-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/tools/rc/delegation/2022/10/16/rc-delegation-tool-update-rc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/tools/rc/delegation/2022/10/16/rc-delegation-tool-update-rc.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc">![](https://images.ecency.com/DQmcXEvn33Sph3AMpajUr46mCxbM4GZFKYupgof5aaHQnZQ/hivewp20.png)

In my [yesterdays post over here](https://peakd.com/hive-139531/@primersion/rc-delegation-tool) I have introduced a new RC delegation tool, which you can access at https://primersion.com/rc.

I implemented a few small improvements, to make the tool even more useful. I would love to see some of those implemented over at PeakD and other frontends in the future as well.

Thanks again for @louis88 for a few more useful inputs.

This post will explain the improvements and how to calculate the equivalent HP amount for your RC delegations.

## Improvements
The biggest change I made to the tool is adding an HP mode, which allows you to specifiy the RC you want to delegate in an HP equivalent amount. **This does not mean that you will be delegating HP, it's just a conversion as it is more understandable as the large RC values.**

![](https://images.ecency.com/DQmWUWfskVyE5LWqPyrYTzwfTpRHCuCr4JbcpLG5f36vmvs/image.png)

You can switch between RC and HP mode using the toggle button on the top. Depending on the selected mode, the input field and the quick action buttons will then specify the amount of RC to delegate in the equivalent amount of HP or in RC directly.
The delegate button on the right will always show you both values:

![](https://images.ecency.com/DQmRWSakaPaFmGTmoTrWCzcUQMoPLCjEGWiBNg5wSdffdtr/image.png)

Additionally I have updated the table with a progress bar for every account you are delegating to. You can easily see, which of them are running out of RC and delegate more to them:

![](https://images.ecency.com/DQmRV8vGPYxxuax9mcN4TLRSqUJ9oToNovymWNVsZCE1gsm/image.png)

Furthermore the table has an additional column showing the equivalent amount of HP, converted from the amount of RC you delegated.
Above the table your total delegations are shown.

The introduction of HP makes the tool much more user friendly and easier to use, so **I would suggest that all frontends will display it that way in the future or add a dual mode to switch between the different units.**

## RC -&gt; HP Calculation

RC is a very "abstract" unit and you easily get confused with those large numbers that single transactions will take e.g. my current total number of resource credits is `63,083,017,640,811`

Humans just aren't great with large numbers, which is why we usually introduce abbreviatons for them. The following list shows an example of such (you probably are familiar with them from hard drive storage):
```
1 K = 1,000
1 M = 1,000,000
1 G = 1,000,000,000
1 T = 1,000,000,000,000
1 P = 1,000,000,000,000,000
...
```
Like this the total RC of my account could be written as `63.083T`.

One other useful thing is transforming values into some other value, which we are more familiar with.
In case of Hive the first thing that comes into mind is HP of course. HP itself is actually also a converted value, based on VESTS. To calculate the HP of your account you first have to calculate the "Hive per Vests", which is done by fetching the dynamic global properties of the Hive chain and diving the total vesting fund by the total vesting shares:
```
hive_per_vests =  total_vesting_fund_hive / total_vesting_shares_hive;
```
Now you can calculate the HP of your account by multiplying the resulting value with the total vests of your account e.g. `69,702,435 *  0.000553 ~ 38,545 HP` for my account.

### So how to convert RC into HP?

RC itself is directly related to VESTS, so for converting RC to HP you multiply it by `hive_per_vests` and divide by `10^6`:
```
amount_hp = amount_rc * hive_per_vests / 10^6
```
e.g. `1,000,000,000 RC = 1G RC ~ 0.553 HP` as of now.

As I already mentioned above I have added a mode to the delegation tool, which allows specifying the amount of RC you want to delegate in an HP equivalent, as this is a unit we are more familiar with and tend to understand better.

---

Let me know what you think about the changes above and if you have any other suggestions for improving usabilty - more new things are to come, so stay tuned.

<center>
<a href="https://vote.hive.uno/@primersion" target="_blank">
![](https://images.ecency.com/DQmePAAbBHNZCaxS46bPGXX2zkCSvrsYuY4Df35uxy7fAXN/primersion_banner.png)</a>

[Vote for my HIVE witness using Keychain.](https://vote.hive.uno/@primersion)
</center>
</div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@primersion",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/rc-delegation-tool-update-rc",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-primersion-rc-delegation-tool-update-rc img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://ecency.com/hive-169321/@primersion/rc-delegation-tool-update-rc">RC Delegation Tool Update + RC -&gt; HP calculation</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@primersion">@primersion</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>primersion</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="rc" /><category term="delegation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post will explain the improvements and how to calculate the equivalent HP amount for your RC delegations.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.ecency.com/DQmcXEvn33Sph3AMpajUr46mCxbM4GZFKYupgof5aaHQnZQ/hivewp20.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.ecency.com/DQmcXEvn33Sph3AMpajUr46mCxbM4GZFKYupgof5aaHQnZQ/hivewp20.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hive SQL - Hardfork 26 support</title><link href="https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/15/hivesql-update-hf26.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hive SQL - Hardfork 26 support" /><published>2022-10-15T09:57:57-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T09:57:57-07:00</updated><id>https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/15/hivesql-update-hf26</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hivedocs.info/news/sql/database/2022/10/15/hivesql-update-hf26.html"><![CDATA[<div id="content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26">![](https://i.imgur.com/bzVnVHr.png)

The hardfork 26 (codename Evolution) has been activated a few days ago as all top 20 witnesses are now running the v1.26 code on their nodes ([see here](https://hive.arcange.eu/witnesses)).

My API servers have also been upgraded to the new code and are now providing HiveSQL with new data. 

Thanks to the mirrornet, I have been able to prepare HiveSQL to fully support the new (virtual) operations now available with this new version.

### What's new?

While no new operations were added during this hardfork, this is not the case for virtual operations.

As a reminder, Virtual Operations are operations resulting from the activity on the blockchain but, unlike classic operations, they are not initiated by users.

And since hardfork 26, no less than 7 additional Virtual Operations are now available to better monitor what is happening in the blockchain.

### New tables

* **VOCollateralizedConvertImmediateConversion**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|owner|The account requesting the conversion|
|requestid|The request identifier|
|hbd_out|Amount of HBD sent to the account|

This virtual operation is triggered after a collateralized_convert operation is issued to convert HIVE to HBD. 

Half of the HIVE amount is converted immediately into HBD (using the minimum witnesses price feed for the last 3.5 days) and sent to the owner.

* **VODHFConversions**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|treasury|The account of the DHF|
|hive_amount_in|The amount of HIVE to convert|
|hbd_amount_out|The amount of HBD generated|

When a user transfer HIVE to the DHF account (hive.fund), the amount is immediately converted to HBD and this virtual operation is generated.

This virtual operation is also generated during block processing every day during daily proposal maintenance.

**Note:** a portion of the HIVE on the treasury balance is converted to HBD and thus increases the funds available for proposals.

* **VODHFFundings**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|treasury|The account of the DHF|
|additional_funds|The amount of HIVE to convert|
|additional_funds_symbol|HBD|

This virtual operation is generated during block processing every proposal maintenance period.

**Note:** while the DHF receives part of inflation every block, this virtual operation is generated only when there are proposal payouts.

* **VOHardforks**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|hardfork_id|Hardfork number|

This virtual operation is generated during block processing every time new hardfork is activated.

* **VOLimitOrderCancelleds**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|seller||The account who created the order|
|amount_back|The amount of the cancelled order|
|additional_funds_symbol|HIVE or HBD|

This virtual operation is generated every time an existing limit order is canceled. It happens on explicit call (first operation), or in the rare case of filling a limit order (second or third operation) when, after filling most of it, the remaining funds are too small (they would round to zero when sold).

This virtual operation is also generated during block processing for orders that reached their expiration time without being filled.

* **VOPowRewards**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|worker|account mining a block|
|reward|amount received |
|reward_symbol|HIVE|

This virtual operation occurs each time a block is produced. It contains the rewards that are given to witnesses (and previously miners) for their work.

* **VOProducerMisseds**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|producer|Name of the witness who missed a block|

This virtual operation is generated during block processing when a witness failed to produce his block on time.

* **VOProposalFees**

|Column|Description|
|-|-|
|creator|Account creating a proposal|
|treasury|The account of the DHF|
|proposal_id|The proposal identifier|
|fee|The amount paid for creating the proposal|
|fee_symbol|HBD|

This virtual operation is generated every time an account creates a new proposal.

---
**Note:** Many of the above mentioned table may currently only contains no records or  only records from hardfork 26 and later. It is planned to perform a replay of the blockchain to re-inject data relating to previous events.

## Documentation

HiveSQL documentation has been updated and can be viewed at https://docs.hivesql.io

## Support

If you have any questions or remarks, support is provided on the [HiveSQL Discord Channel](https://discord.gg/kyEFDfT).

Thank you.

---
<center>

### Check out my apps and services
<a href="/hive/@hive.engage/stay-connected-with-your-hive-audience-and-catch-attention"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/GiNJqlm.png" /></a><a href="/@hivebuzz"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/B4UTun2.png" /></a><a href="/@hivesql"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/EPN8RW6.png" /></a><a href="/hive/@arcange/introducing-hive-account-recovery"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/6TWeW7V.png" /></a><a href="/@hive.autoclaim"><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ih2pEOw.png" /></a></center>
<center>

### [Vote for me as a witness ![](https://i.imgur.com/2bi4SnT.png)](https://vote.hive.uno/@arcange)</center></div>
<script crossorigin="anonymous" integrity="sha256-4+XzXVhsDmqanXGHaHvgh1gMQKX40OUvDEBTu8JcmNs=" src="https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.5.1.slim.min.js"></script>

<script src="https://unpkg.com/steem-content-renderer"></script>

<!-- <script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/hive-content-renderer/dist/hive-content-renderer.min.js"></script> -->
<script>
  $(document).ready(function() {
    try {
      const renderer = new SteemContentRenderer.DefaultRenderer({
      // const renderer = new HiveContentRenderer({
        baseUrl: "https://hive.blog/",
        breaks: true,
        skipSanitization: false,
        allowInsecureScriptTags: false,
        addNofollowToLinks: true,
        doNotShowImages: false,
        ipfsPrefix: "",
        assetsWidth: 640,
        assetsHeight: 480,
        imageProxyFn: (url) => url,
        usertagUrlFn: (account) => "/@arcange",
        hashtagUrlFn: (hashtag) => "/hivesql-update-hf26",
        isLinkSafeFn: (url) => true,
      });
      
      const inputElem = $('#content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26').html();
      const outputElem = $('#content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26');
      const output = renderer.render(inputElem);
      
      outputElem.html(output);
    } catch(e) {
      console.log(e);
    }
  });
</script>

<style>
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 {
    padding: 0 3rem;
    color: #444444;
    font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif;
    font-size: 16px;
    line-height: 1.8;
    text-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ffffff;
    padding: 0.5rem;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 code {
    background: white;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 a {
    border-bottom: 1px solid #444444; color: #444444; text-decoration: none;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 a:hover {
    border-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 h1 {
    font-size: 2.2em;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 h2, h3, h4, h5 {
    margin-bottom: 0;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 header small {
    color: #999;
    font-size: 50%;
  }
  #content-arcange-hivesql-update-hf26 img {
    max-width: 100%;
  }
</style>

<hr />

<p>
  See: <a href="https://peakd.com/hive-139531/@arcange/hivesql-update-hf26">Hive SQL  - Hardfork 26 support</a>
  by
  <a href="https://hive.blog/@arcange">@arcange</a>
</p>]]></content><author><name>arcange</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="sql" /><category term="database" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[HiveSQL has been updated to fully support the new operation implemented for the hardfork 26 of the blockchain]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.imgur.com/bzVnVHr.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.imgur.com/bzVnVHr.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>